Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we are here with an advanced level lesson.
我是Catherine，今天我们带来了一节高级课程。
That means that we're going to listen to a pretty long and exciting dialogue and then
这意味着我们会听一段相当长且精彩的对话，然后
we'll talk a little bit about what you've heard and some of these cool interesting phrases.
我们会聊聊你听到的内容以及一些酷炫有趣的短语。
That's right.
没错。
Today we have a lesson about planning a crime or planning a bank robbery.
今天我们的课程是关于策划犯罪或抢劫银行的。
Oh, my favorite.
哦，我最喜欢了。
There have been lots of movies about this topic, very fun movies.
关于这个话题有很多电影，非常有趣的电影。
From the beginning of movie making till now, it's a very popular topic.
从电影制作之初到现在，这都是一个很受欢迎的主题。
That's right.
没错。
On this occasion, as Catherine said, it's a nice fun dialogue and we're going to have
这次，正如Catherine所说，这是一段有趣好玩的对话，我们会接触到
a lot of colloquial terms.
很多口语化的表达。
Maybe you won't really understand a couple of different phrases because they're very
可能你会不太理解一些短语，因为它们非常
colloquial.
口语化。
They're very American terms.
它们是很地道的美国用语。
The accents are also, they're a little bit from Boston, kind of like New Jersey maybe
口音也有一点波士顿的味道，可能有点像新泽西
or something.
之类的。
Right.
对。
So, keep an ear out for some of the strange or unusual phrases.
所以，留意一下那些奇怪或不寻常的短语。
We will be talking about them in a moment.
我们稍后会讨论它们。
But don't worry, if you don't understand this dialogue the first time, you'll be hearing
但别担心，如果你第一次没听懂这段对话，你之后还会
it again later.
再听到的。
All right.
好了。
Let's run through this one more time from the top.
让我们从头再过一遍。
I will be positioned here, across from the bank on this park bench.
我会待在这里，银行对面的公园长椅上。
Now according to the intel we got from Jimmy.
根据我们从Jimmy那里得到的情报。
Oh, who's Jimmy?
哦，Jimmy是谁？
Geez, Ralph, pay attention, will ya?
天哪，Ralph，专心点，行吗？
Jimmy's our mole, you know?
Jimmy是我们的内线，知道吗？
The guy on the inside.
那个内部的人。
He's been snooping and passing on the info to us so we can pull this heist off.
他一直在暗中打探并把信息传给我们，这样我们才能成功实施这次抢劫。
Yeah, Ralph, clean the mothballs out of your ears and listen up.
是啊，Ralph，把你耳朵里的樟脑丸清干净，好好听着。
This here is important.
这很重要。
We don't want to end up back in the slammer, do ya?
我们可不想再回到监狱里，对吧？
Your role is pretty important here.
你的角色在这里相当重要。
We're dependent on you, man.
我们全靠你了，老兄。
Okay, okay, I'm listening.
好了，好了，我在听。
Mothballs.
樟脑丸。
Alrighty then.
好吧。
Where was I?
我说到哪儿了？
Yeah, okay, so I'll be on the lookout, sitting here on the bench across from the bank.
对，好的，所以我会放哨，坐在这里银行对面的长椅上。
Nobody moves until I give the go-ahead, all right?
在我发出行动信号之前，谁都不许动，明白吗？
And what's the go-ahead, Ralph?
那信号是什么，Ralph？
You uh, you uh, oh yeah, you'll take off your hat and scratch your head.
你呃，你呃，哦对了，你会摘下帽子挠头。
Right.
对。
When I take my hat off and scratch my head, you do what?
当我摘下帽子挠头时，你做什么？
I get in the box.
我进箱子里。
Right, you get in the box.
对，你进箱子里。
I'll make sure it's all sealed and then posing as the delivery guy, I'll drop off a special
我会确保箱子封好，然后假扮成送货员，送一个特别的
package for the manager.
包裹给经理。
Now according to Jimmy, the bank manager's leaving early on Tuesday, because it's his
根据Jimmy的说法，银行经理周二会提前下班，因为那天是他
wedding anniversary.
的结婚纪念日。
He and the wife are having a romantic rendezvous in the country, so any packages delivered
他和妻子要在乡下浪漫约会，所以任何送到的包裹
will be left unopened in his office until he gets back late on Wednesday.
都会原封不动地放在他办公室里，直到他周三晚些时候回来。
Which gives us access to his office for at least 12 hours.
这样我们就有至少12小时可以进入他的办公室。
Okay Ralph, this is where you come in.
好了Ralph，这就轮到你了。
Where are you?
你在哪儿？
I'm standing right next to you, Sammy.
我就站在你旁边，Sammy。
Oh sorry, Sam.
哦，抱歉，Sam。
I'm in the box, right here in that box.
我在箱子里，就在那个箱子里。
And what do you do once I deliver you to the manager's office?
我把你送到经理办公室后，你做什么？
I stay in the box until the bank is closed, and then I get out of the box.
我待在箱子里直到银行关门，然后我出来。
And then?
然后呢？
What next, Ralph?
接下来做什么，Ralph？
Oh for Pete's sake, this is never going to work.
哦，天哪，这计划根本行不通。
Hey, give me a chance here, fellas.
嘿，给我个机会，伙计们。
I crack the safe and then, then I take the money, and then I, um, I get back in the box.
我撬开保险柜，然后，然后我拿钱，然后我，呃，我再回到箱子里。
Atta boy, Ralph.
好样的，Ralph。
In the morning, I come back to the bank, say there's been a mix-up with the delivery I
早上，我回到银行，说送货出了点差错，
made, and take the special package back here.
然后把那个特别的包裹拿回来。
Alright, let's get some sleep.
好了，我们睡会儿吧。
It's a big day tomorrow, fellas.
明天是大日子，伙计们。
A perfect plan, Sammy!
完美的计划，Sammy！
It went off without a hitch!
一切顺利，毫无差错！
Let's open this up and get Ralph out of here so we can start counting the money.
我们打开这个箱子，把Ralph弄出来，这样就能开始数钱了。
Phew, I sure am glad to see you guys.
呼，真高兴见到你们。
I was sure getting lonely with no one to talk.
没人说话，我真是闷坏了。
That's nice.
那挺好。
Okay, how much?
好了，多少钱？
Uh, really?
呃，真的吗？
Really, really, really glad.
真的，真的，真的很高兴。
Money, Ralph, money!
钱，拉尔夫，钱！
Oh man, I knew I forgot something.
哦天哪，我就知道忘了什么东西。
Damn it.
该死。
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So, um, obviously this guy Ralph, I don't know why, always the one robber whose name
所以，嗯，很明显这个叫拉尔夫的家伙，我不知道为什么，总是那个名字叫拉尔夫的劫匪
is Ralph is not very clever.
不太聪明。
No, it doesn't mean that Ralphs are generally not smart people, but yeah, I think you're
不，这并不意味着叫拉尔夫的人通常都不聪明，但我觉得你说得
right.
对。
There's usually...
通常有...
Yeah, like in bank robberies or something, like for example in the old movies, always
是啊，比如在银行抢劫之类的场景里，就像老电影里那样，总是
Ralph was the one that was messing things up.
拉尔夫把事情搞砸。
Oh, Ralph.
哦，拉尔夫。
Well, let's find out what Ralph screwed up today.
好吧，我们来看看今天拉尔夫搞砸了什么。
First of all, we've got the guys Sammy, Ralph, and Frankie who are talking about the plan.
首先，我们有萨米、拉尔夫和弗兰基这几个家伙在讨论计划。
And Sammy mentions that he had the intel from Jimmy.
萨米提到他从吉米那里得到了情报。
Okay, so when we talk about intel, we're talking about information, right?
好的，所以当我们说情报时，我们指的是信息，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So intel is a word that's short for intelligence or facts or information.
所以情报这个词是智力或事实或信息的简称。
That's right.
没错。
So you can talk about intelligence as maybe you're very smart, you're very intelligent,
所以你可以说智力，可能指你很聪明，很有智慧，
but when we talk about intelligence, we talk about gathering information in order to help
但当我们谈论情报时，我们指的是收集信息以帮助
us accomplish an objective.
我们实现目标。
For example, in movies about the CIA, we often hear them talk about gathering intel.
例如，在关于中情局的电影里，我们经常听到他们谈论收集情报。
That means collecting facts.
这意味着收集事实。
Right.
对。
Very good.
很好。
So they had intel from Jimmy about the bank and the layout.
所以他们从吉米那里得到了关于银行和布局的情报。
And well, they were like, who's Jimmy?
然后他们问，吉米是谁？
And Sammy says that, well, he's our mole, you know, the guy on the inside.
萨米说，嗯，他是我们的内线，你知道，就是内部的人。
A mole.
内线。
So mole is an animal.
所以鼹鼠是一种动物。
But in cases of intelligence, or maybe in this case, a bank robbery, spying, a mole
但在情报领域，或者在这种情况下，银行抢劫、间谍活动中，内线
is a person who's basically stealing information.
是一个基本上在偷信息的人。
So for example, if I work in the CIA, but I'm selling information from the CIA to the
例如，如果我在中情局工作，但我把中情局的信息卖给
French government, I'm a mole.
法国政府，我就是个内线。
Right.
对。
So you're basically like a spy.
所以你基本上就像个间谍。
Yes.
是的。
You're a person on the inside.
你是内部的人。
And that's what they mean when he says, he's our guy on the inside.
这就是他说“他是我们内部的人”时的意思。
You're inside the enemy's territory or you're inside their organization.
你在敌人的地盘里，或者你在他们的组织内部。
Exactly.
完全正确。
So for example, have you seen the show 24?
比如，你看过《24小时》这部剧吗？
Yeah, with Jack Bauer.
看过，有杰克·鲍尔的那个。
Well, they often have this problem of moles inside the organization.
嗯，他们经常有组织内部内线的问题。
So maybe the terrorists have a guy on the inside.
所以可能恐怖分子有内部的人。
That's right.
没错。
He's a mole.
他是个内线。
So they have somebody that has penetrated their organization.
所以他们有人渗透进了他们的组织。
Exactly.
完全正确。
Okay, so they talk about the mole and how they are going to pull this heist off.
好的，所以他们讨论内线以及他们如何成功实施这次抢劫。
Okay, so the phrase here is to pull off a heist.
好的，这里的短语是“成功实施抢劫”。
First of all, what's a heist?
首先，什么是抢劫？
Well, a heist is a robbery, is basically a robbery.
嗯，抢劫就是盗窃，基本上就是盗窃。
Yeah, it's another word for robbery.
是啊，是盗窃的另一个说法。
It's kind of old though.
不过有点老派。
You don't really say it anymore, right?
现在不太常说了，对吧？
No, you can say it's a heist movie or it's a movie about a heist.
不，你可以说这是一部抢劫电影，或者一部关于抢劫的电影。
It's almost like a genre.
这几乎成了一种类型。
Yeah.
是啊。
So there's a basic storyline where they plan the robbery, they do the robbery, something
所以有一个基本的故事线：他们计划抢劫，实施抢劫，然后出了
goes wrong, what's going to happen?
问题，接下来会发生什么？
So that's a heist.
这就是抢劫。
Very good.
很好。
So a heist is something that was planned out, like a robbery that's planned out.
所以抢劫是计划好的事情，比如计划好的盗窃。
It's not really if you come up to someone and say, give me your wallet.
不像你走到某人面前说，把钱包给我。
That's not really a heist.
那不算抢劫。
No, that's a stick up.
不，那是持械抢劫。
Right.
对。
But a heist is something that you pull off.
但抢劫是你成功实施的事情。
So to pull off is to succeed.
所以“成功实施”就是成功做到。
To accomplish.
完成。
So I pulled it off.
所以我成功了。
I was able to do it.
我做到了。
So you pulled off the heist.
所以你成功实施了抢劫。
Very good.
很好。
And well, they were talking about if they do it, they don't want to get caught because
然后他们讨论如果做了，他们不想被抓，因为
they don't want to go back to the slammer.
他们不想再回监狱了。
The slammer.
监狱。
Yeah, well, I don't blame them.
是啊，我不怪他们。
I wouldn't want to go to the slammer either.
我也不想进监狱。
So what is the slammer?
那“slammer”是什么意思？
The slammer.
监狱。
The big house.
大房子（监狱的俚语）。
Right.
对。
Lock up, the slammer, the big house.
关起来、监狱、大房子。
All these are colloquial synonyms for prison, for jail.
这些都是监狱或牢房的口语同义词。
Jail.
牢房。
Normally we say prison or jail, like it's a maximum security prison, like prison break,
通常我们说监狱或牢房，比如最高安全级别的监狱，就像《越狱》那样，
the TV show.
那部电视剧。
Right.
对。
But in colloquial English, we often say slammer.
但在英语口语中，我们常说“slammer”。
Okay.
好的。
The slammer or the big house.
“Slammer”或“big house”。
Okay.
好的。
So they were talking that they don't want to go back to the slammer.
所以他们刚才在说不想回监狱。
And now when they were actually planning out the crime, he says, well, you wait until I
现在当他们实际策划犯罪时，他说，嗯，你等我
give you the go ahead.
给你信号。
Okay.
好的。
So this is the plan.
所以这就是计划。
He's going to wait for a sign.
他要等一个信号。
The go ahead means a sign that indicates that it's time to do something.
“Go ahead”意思是表示该行动了的信号。
Okay.
好的。
So for example, so in this case, what is that sign?
比如，在这个例子中，那个信号是什么？
The sign or the go ahead is he'll take off his hat and scratch his head.
信号或“go ahead”就是他摘下帽子挠头。
Okay.
好的。
So that's a sign that means it's okay to proceed.
所以那是一个表示可以继续的信号。
It's okay to continue.
可以继续了。
So you can also say, okay, when we're ready to go, Marco, I'll give you the go ahead.
所以你也可以说，好的，当我们准备好出发时，马可，我会给你信号。
Okay.
好的。
Just wait for me to wave.
等我挥手就行。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
That's a signal.
那是一个信号。
Exactly.
没错。
All right.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
Now moving on, we have a French word here, but that's used very commonly in English.
现在继续，我们这里有一个法语词，但在英语中很常用。
And they said, okay, we have a rendezvous.
他们说了，好的，我们有个约会。
Okay.
好的。
So a rendezvous is a meetup or a time or place where people are connecting together.
所以“rendezvous”是见面或人们聚在一起的时间或地点。
So for example, in a heist, you could say we're going to rob the bank and then we will
比如，在抢劫中，你可以说我们要抢银行，然后两小时后
rendezvous at our favorite restaurant in two hours.
在我们最喜欢的餐厅会合。
Okay.
好的。
So a rendezvous is to meet up, to get together.
所以“rendezvous”就是碰面、聚在一起。
Right.
对。
But in this case, they're talking about a romantic rendezvous.
但在这个例子中，他们在谈论一个浪漫的约会。
So this means a trip with a lover.
所以这指的是和情人的旅行。
So it's a little bit different, right?
所以有点不同，对吧？
He and his wife are having a romantic rendezvous in the country.
他和妻子在乡下有个浪漫的约会。
Okay.
好的。
That means that they're going to have a romantic meeting.
那意味着他们要有一个浪漫的会面。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
And now this next phrase is very, very interesting.
现在下一个短语非常非常有趣。
It's very common to hear it as well.
也很常见。
I think like moms say it a lot.
我觉得妈妈们常说。
Oh, for Pete's sake.
哦，看在彼得的份上。
Well, I don't know who Pete is, honestly.
嗯，说实话我不知道彼得是谁。
But this means my gosh or come on or I'm so tired of this.
但这意思是“我的天”或“拜托”或“我受够了”。
So you're a little bit exasperated.
所以你有点恼火。
Maybe you're a little bit irritated.
可能你有点烦躁。
Oh, for Pete's sake, Marco.
哦，看在彼得的份上，马可。
Stop giving me examples.
别再给我举例子了。
I'm just, I'm done hearing them.
我真是听够了。
Yeah.
是啊。
So there are a lot of other ways to say this, right?
还有很多其他说法，对吧？
Yeah.
对。
So you could say for goodness sake.
所以你可以说“看在老天的份上”。
For goodness sake or oh, for heaven's sake.
看在老天的份上，或者哦，看在老天的份上。
For heaven's sake.
看在老天的份上。
And finally, for God's sake.
最后，看在上帝的份上。
Right.
对。
But this one you have to be careful because some people who are religious might be offended
但这个要小心，因为有些信教的人可能会被冒犯
if you use it.
如果你用的话。
So if that's the case, then you would just rather go with Pete's sake, heaven's sake
所以如果是那样，你最好用“Pete's sake”或“heaven's sake”。
or goodness sake.
看在老天的份上。
Okay.
好的。
For goodness sake.
看在老天的份上。
It's a very common phrase and as you say, it's for when you're a little bit irritated.
这是一个很常见的短语，正如你所说，用于你有点烦躁的时候。
It's like oh, for goodness sake.
就像“哦，看在老天的份上”。
Stop complaining.
别抱怨了。
Exactly.
没错。
Right?
对吧？
Okay.
好的。
And now for our last word.
现在来看我们的最后一个词。
You may have seen the word fellas.
你可能见过“fellas”这个词。
Fellas.
伙计们。
So this comes from the word fellow, person, man.
这个词来自“fellow”，意思是人、男人。
But oftentimes in these kind of movies or stories about heists or crimes, the men talk
但在这种关于抢劫或犯罪的电影或故事中，男人们经常
to each other using the word fella or fellas.
用“fella”或“fellas”互相称呼。
So come on, fellas.
所以，“来吧，伙计们”。
Let's go.
我们走。
That means come on, guys.
意思是“来吧，大家”。
Come on, everyone.
来吧，所有人。
Okay.
好的。
Yeah.
是的。
So this is always about men, not like a group of women would use this.
所以这总是关于男人的，不像一群女人会用这个词。
And it's something that's a little bit older.
而且这是一个有点老式的说法。
We don't really say this like oh, me and my fellas, we're going to go to the store.
我们不会真的说“哦，我和我的伙计们，我们要去商店”。
You would say this more in old time English.
你更可能在老式英语中这么说。
Yeah.
是的。
You can see it maybe in some movies when somebody comes up and greets other people, other guys,
你可能会在一些电影中看到，当有人过来问候其他人、其他家伙时，
he would say hey, fellas.
他会说“嘿，伙计们”。
Exactly.
没错。
Or there's a mafia movie.
或者有一部黑帮电影。
It's about the American mafia called Goodfellas.
是关于美国黑帮的，叫《好家伙》。
Very good.
非常好。
It's a very famous one.
这是一部非常著名的电影。
So it kind of gives you that feeling of an older English like the 1940s to the 1970s.
所以它给人一种老式英语的感觉，比如1940年代到1970年代。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
So we've got a lot of things going on in this bank robbery.
所以这次银行抢劫中有很多事情发生。
Why don't we go back, listen to the dialogue one last time and we'll be back in a little
我们为什么不回去，再听一遍对话，然后我们一会儿
bit.
再回来。
Alright let's run through this one more time from the top.
好的，让我们从头再过一遍。
I will be positioned here across from the bank on this park bench.
我会坐在银行对面的公园长椅上。
Now according to the intel we got from Jimmy.
根据我们从吉米那里得到的情报。
Oh, who's Jimmy?
哦，吉米是谁？
Geez, Ralph, pay attention, will ya?
天哪，拉尔夫，注意点，好吗？
Jimmy's our mole, you know?
吉米是我们的内线，知道吗？
The guy on the inside.
那个内部的人。
He's been snooping and passing on the info to us so we can pull this heist off.
他一直在暗中打探并把信息传给我们，这样我们才能完成这次抢劫。
Yeah, Ralph, clean the mothballs out of your ears and listen up.
是啊，拉尔夫，把耳朵里的樟脑丸清干净，好好听着。
This here is important.
这很重要。
We don't want to end up back in the slammer, do ya?
我们可不想再回到监狱里，对吧？
Your role is pretty important here.
你的角色在这里相当重要。
We're dependent on you, man.
我们全靠你了，老兄。
Okay, okay, I'm listening.
好的，好的，我在听。
Mothballs.
樟脑丸。
Alrighty then.
好的，那么。
Where was I?
我说到哪儿了？
Yeah, okay.
是的，好的。
So, I'll be on the lookout, sitting here on the bench across from the bank.
所以，我会放哨，坐在银行对面的长椅上。
Nobody moves until I give the go-ahead, alright?
在我发出行动信号之前，谁都不许动，明白吗？
And what's the go-ahead, Ralph?
那行动信号是什么，拉尔夫？
You uh, you uh, oh yeah, you'll take off your hat and scratch your head.
你呃，你呃，哦对了，你会摘下帽子挠头。
Right.
对。
When I take my hat off and scratch my head, you do what?
当我摘下帽子挠头时，你做什么？
I get in the box.
我进箱子。
Right, you get in the box.
对，你进箱子。
I'll make sure it's all sealed and then posing as the delivery guy, I'll drop off a special
我会确保箱子封好，然后假扮成送货员，给经理送一个特别的
package for the manager.
包裹。
Now, according to Jimmy, the bank manager's leaving early on Tuesday, because it's his
现在，根据吉米的情报，银行经理周二会提前下班，因为那天是他
wedding anniversary.
的结婚纪念日。
He and the wife are having a romantic rendezvous in the country, so any packages delivered
他和妻子要在乡下浪漫约会，所以任何送到的包裹
will be left unopened in his office until he gets back late on Wednesday.
都会原封不动地放在他办公室里，直到他周三晚回来。
Which gives us access to his office for at least 12 hours.
这样我们就有至少12小时可以进入他的办公室。
Okay Ralph, this is where you come in.
好的拉尔夫，这就是你出场的时候了。
Where are you?
你在哪儿？
I'm standing right next to you, Sammy.
我就站在你旁边，萨米。
Oh, sorry Sam, I'm in the box, right here, in that box.
哦，抱歉萨姆，我在箱子里，就在这儿，在那个箱子里。
And what do you do once I deliver you to the manager's office?
一旦我把你送到经理办公室，你做什么？
I stay in the box until the bank is closed, and then I get out of the box.
我待在箱子里直到银行关门，然后我出来。
And then?
然后呢？
What next, Ralph?
接下来呢，拉尔夫？
Oh, for Pete's sake, this is never going to work.
哦，老天爷，这根本行不通。
Hey, give me a chance here, fellas.
嘿，给我个机会嘛，伙计们。
I crack the safe and then, then I take the money, and then I, um, I get back in the box.
我撬开保险柜，然后，然后拿走钱，然后我，呃，再回到箱子里。
Atta boy, Ralph.
好样的，拉尔夫。
In the morning I come back to the bank, say there's been a mix-up with the delivery I
早上我回到银行，说送货出了点差错，我
made and take the special package back here.
把那个特殊包裹拿回这里。
Alright, let's get some sleep.
好了，咱们睡会儿吧。
It's a big day tomorrow, fellas.
明天是大日子，伙计们。
A perfect plan, Sammy!
完美的计划，萨米！
It went off without a hitch!
一切顺利，毫无差错！
Let's open this up and get Ralph out of here so we can start counting the money.
咱们打开这个，把拉尔夫弄出来，好开始数钱。
Phew, I sure am glad to see you guys.
呼，真高兴见到你们。
I was sure getting lonely with no one to talk.
没人说话，我真是闷坏了。
That's nice.
那挺好。
Okay, how much?
好了，多少钱？
Uh, really?
呃，真的吗？
Really, really, really glad.
真的，真的，真的高兴。
Money, Ralph, money!
钱，拉尔夫，钱啊！
Oh, man, I knew I forgot something.
哦，天哪，我就知道忘了什么。
Damn it.
该死。
Okay, so, someone proclaimed at the end of the dialogue that everything went off without
好，所以，有人在对话结尾说一切进行得
a hitch.
毫无差错。
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
Is this true?
这是真的吗？
No.
不是。
What does it mean if something went without a hitch?
如果某事“went without a hitch”是什么意思？
It went off without a hitch means there was not even one problem.
“Went off without a hitch”意思是没有任何问题。
It went off, it went perfectly.
它进行得很顺利，完美无缺。
Smoothly.
顺畅。
Smoothly, yes.
顺畅，没错。
Okay.
好的。
And it didn't because, well, these robbers didn't actually rob anyone.
但事实并非如此，因为，嗯，这些劫匪根本没抢到任何人。
Right, he forgot to get the money.
对，他忘了拿钱。
Right, so he's kind of an idiot.
对，所以他有点像个白痴。
Right.
没错。
But there are actually a lot of good movies.
但其实有很多好电影。
I think the most recent one about bank robberies is Ocean's Eleven, Ocean's Twelve, Ocean's
我觉得最近关于银行抢劫的电影是《十一罗汉》、《十二罗汉》、《十三罗汉》。
Thirteen.
对，没错。
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
Those are all about big heists.
那些都是关于大劫案的。
Big heists.
大劫案。
And I think they mentioned the word heist a couple of times in that movie.
我觉得那部电影里提了好几次“heist”这个词。
Yeah, definitely.
对，肯定有。
So, there was a movie with Clive Owen a few years ago called The Inside Man that was maybe
所以，几年前有一部克里夫·欧文的电影叫《局内人》，可能是我很久以来看过最好的劫案电影之一。
one of the best heist movies I've seen in a long time.
对，那部电影确实很好。
Yeah, that was a really good movie.
I think also Swordfish was a pretty good movie with John Travolta.
我觉得《剑鱼行动》也是一部不错的电影，有约翰·特拉沃尔塔。
Yeah, I remember that one, too.
对，我也记得那部。
Yeah, I like it when the bad guys win, you know, because it's a little bit more interesting.
对，我喜欢坏人赢的结局，你知道，因为那样更有意思一点。
Yeah, I guess you could say that.
对，我想可以这么说。
I don't think the public likes this.
我觉得公众不喜欢这样。
Well, in The Inside Man, the bad guy is kind of a good guy, but he wins.
嗯，在《局内人》里，坏人有点像好人，但他赢了。
Yeah, I like that.
对，我喜欢那样。
So, but it's a very interesting topic and I don't know, I haven't really heard of many
所以，这是个很有趣的话题，而且我不知道，我最近没怎么听说
bank robberies nowadays anymore.
银行抢劫案了。
Not so much.
不太多了。
I think security in banks is pretty good, but I'd be very curious to hear from our users
我觉得银行的安全措施相当好，但我很好奇我们的用户
if they have any favorite heist stories or movies, real or fake.
有没有什么最喜欢的劫案故事或电影，真实的或虚构的。
Both are okay.
两者都可以。
You can let us know on our website, EnglishPod.com.
你可以在我们的网站 EnglishPod.com 上告诉我们。
That's right.
没错。
Thanks for having us, everyone.
感谢大家收听。
Bye.
再见。
See you soon.
回头见。